Dwight D. Gunning

dwight@dwightgunning.com | http://www.dwightgunning.com | @dwightgunning | +31 6 23 63 83 44

Background

Dwight is an Amsterdam based entrepreneur and software engineer. He brings over 10 years experience as a Software Engineer, Technology Architect, Team Lead and Project Manager working both in large enterprises and at startups.

Dwight is product focussed with the ability to drive the full lifecycle from requirements and design through to implementation, testing and release. His full stack technical expertise is with Python/Django, HTML/CSS/Javascript and Web Services along with performance and scalability.

Skills

HTML5, CSS, Javascript	Python, Django, Flask	Google Analytics, Mixpanel
Twitter Bootstrap, Angular.js	Postgres, MongoDB, Redis	Optimizely, CrazyEgg
Sass, Gulp, Bower, Grunt, NPM	Nginx, Gunicorn, Supervisor	Stripe, Braintree payments
Website performance optimisation	Amazon AWS, Linode	CDNs, New Relic

Work Experience

Freelance Web Developer & Software Engineer

July 2015 - Present

In recent months I have worked on both commercial and personal entrepreneurial projects:

ABN AMRO - Data Center Services ITSM Portal

Under a freelance contract via Logicalis SMC to IBM, I worked on the frontend for a new ITSM service portal. This included HTML/CSS/Javascript and use of the company's endorsed style guidelines. Extensive cross-browser testing was also performed.

Knownly.net

This side-project allows anybody to publish a website from within a Dropbox folder. I designed, implemented and now manage the service from front-to-back.

Senior Software Engineer @ The Cloakroom B.V.

October 2014 - July 2015

The Cloakroom is an online personal shopping service for men. As lead software engineer I coordinated a range of business stakeholders and have oversight across the major customer-facing and back-office systems.

Partner & Technology Lead @ Epic Labs B.V.

September 2013 - August 2014

Epic Labs was incorporated by three entrepreneurs to rapidly execute on startup ideas. I led product development for three beta products that were launched:

Butler - Delivery logistics for online groceries

My role for this project was to design a landing page that would present the value proposition to early adopters and a series of back-office systems in support of the pilot.

Beagle - meta-search for online courses (MOOCs etc.)

This project involved development of a series of web scrapers based on the *Scrapy* framework. The technology built indexed and maintain fresh data for over 10,000 courses. The website was built with *Django* with of *Celery* and *ElasticSearch*.

Founder @ Revirda, Inc.

January 2012 - September 2013

Revirda was a mobile based Taxi Driver Intelligence System. As the company founder I developed the full set of *Python* backend services, APIs, as well as the Web (*Backbone.js*), *Android* and *iOS* clients. The website and backend were developed with *Django*, *Websockets* and extensive use of *Celery* for asynchronous task parallelisation and *Redis* for low latency, volatile data storage.

Manager @ Accenture

Jan 2005 - December 2009 (Australia) and Jan 2010 - Dec 2013 (The Netherlands)
While working at Accenture I performed a diverse range of Subject Matter Expert and Project Management roles. A major highlight was my role as a manager leading a distributed team of ten developers to deliver a trading platform for a major Dutch bank. Also, as a subject matter expert in website performance, I developed operational procedures and training programs for a major Dutch oil and gas company with workers based in 4 continents.

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology @ Queensland University of Technology

• *Major:* Software Engineering

• Grade Point Average: 5.5 (scale 3 through to 7)

References

Available on request.